William Carey Crane papers, Inclusive: 1809-1944, Bulk: 1834-1885
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Literary Productions, 1827-1933, undated; 6
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1865 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1866-1869 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1882-1883 February (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1883 May-December 19 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1883 December 20 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1884 January-March (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1884 July-1885 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Biographical Materials: Catherine Jane Shepherd Crane, undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Biographical Materials: William Carey Crane: (1 of 7), undated (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Biographical Materials: William Carey Crane: (2 of 7), undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Biographical Materials: William Carey Crane: (3 of 7), 1909, undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Biographical Materials: William Carey Crane: (4 of 7), undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Materials: William Carey Crane: (5 of 7), undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Materials: William Carey Crane: (6 of 7), undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Materials: William Carey Crane: (7 of 7), undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Sermons, 1834-1837 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Sermons, 1838-1839 March 24 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Sermons, 1839 March 31-April (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Sermons, 1839 May (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Sermons, 1839 June-July 21 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Sermons, 1839 July 28-October 11 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Sermons, 1839 October 15-November (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Sermons, 1840 January-February (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Sermons, 1840 March-April (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Sermons, 1840 May (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Sermons, 1840 June-December (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Sermons, 1841 February-May (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Sermons, 1841 July-August (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Sermons, 1841 October-December (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Sermons, 1842-1844 October (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Sermons, 1844 November-1845 January (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Sermons, 1845 February-May (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Sermons, 1845 June-October (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Sermons, 1846 February-April (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Sermons, 1846 May-September (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Sermons, 1846 October-1847 March (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Sermons, 1847 February-November (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Sermons, 1848-1850 May (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Sermons, 1850 October-December (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Sermons, 1854-1855 April (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Sermons, 1855 September-November (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Sermons, 1857-1862 February (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Sermons, 1862 September-1866 February (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Sermons, 1866 March-1867 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Sermons, 1868-1878 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: French, 1831 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: Grammar, 1832 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: Greek, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Notebook: Greek, 1836 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Notebook: Greek and Hebrew, 1836-1837, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Notebook: Lectures: Language, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: Lectures: Logic, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: Lectures: Religion, 1874 July (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: Lectures: Science, 1834-1878 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: Lectures: Science, 1849-1850 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: Lectures: Sermons, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: Lectures: Theology, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: Old Testament, 1836 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: Personal, 1830 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: Prophecies, 1837 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: Prophecies and Greek, 1836-1837 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: Royston Crane, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: Scripture, 1837 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: Sermons, 1863 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: Sermons, 1867, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: Sermons, 1874-1883 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: Sermons, 1872, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: Sermons, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Printed Materials: Crane Family, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Printed Materials: “Gospel of Mark”: Chinese, 1880 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Printed Materials: Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1847-1854 June (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Printed Materials: Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1854 July-1858 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Printed Materials: Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 1869-1870, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Printed Materials: Mississippi Baptist Convention, 1845-1854 November 9 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Printed Materials: Mississippi Baptist Convention, 1854 November 9-1856 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Printed Materials: Mississippi Baptist Convention, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Printed Materials: Mount Lebanon Controversy, 1863 March-May 15 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials: Mount Lebanon Controversy, 1863 May (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials: Mount Lebanon Controversy, 1863 June (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials: Mount Lebanon Controversy, 1863 June-July (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Printed Materials: Mount Lebanon Controversy, 1863 August-1864 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Printed Materials: Southern Baptist Convention: (1 of 2), 1845-1871 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Printed Materials: Southern Baptist Convention: (2 of 2), 1845-1871 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Printed Materials: Texas Baptist Convention: (1 of 5), 1846-1884 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Printed Materials: Texas Baptist Convention: (2 of 5), 1846-1884 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Printed Materials: Texas Baptist Convention: (3 of 5), 1846-1884 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Printed Materials: Texas Baptist Convention: (4 of 5), 1846-1884 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Printed Materials: Texas Baptist Convention: (5 of 5), 1846-1884 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Printed Materials: Charles Webb, 1927-1928 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Printed Materials: General: (1 of 2), 1842-1871, undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Printed Materials: General: (2 of 2), 1842-1871, undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Printed Materials: General, 1857-1933 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Addresses, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Notes: Exegesis, undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Family, 1895, undated (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Notes: Ministerial, 1834-1841 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Notes: Mississippi Female College, 1847-1853 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Notes: Literary Extracts, 1835-1842 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Notes: Personal, undated (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Notes: Royston Crane, undated (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Notes: “Rules for Grammar”, undated (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Notes: School, undated (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1836-1840 April 12 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1840 April 26-1841 May (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1841 June-1845 July (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1845 August-1846 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1847-1856 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1857-1868 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1869-1873 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1874-1878 October (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Notes: Sermons, 1878 November-1884 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Notes: Sermons: (1 of 2), undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Notes: Sermons: (2 of 2), undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Notes: Washington County, 1876 June (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Notes: Washington County, 1876 July, undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Notes: General, 1880, undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Addresses: Fluvana Female Institute, Monrovia, Hamilton Theological Seminary, 1835-1864 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Addresses: Inauguration at Baylor: (1 of 2), 1864 January 18 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Addresses: Inauguration at Baylor: (2 of 2), 1864 January 18 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Addresses: Institution of Odd Fellowship, 1847 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Addresses: “Knowledge”, 1866 April 16 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Addresses: Marvin College, 1883 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Addresses: Marvin College and National Education Association, 1873-1876 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Addresses: Masonic Lodge: Bastrop, Texas, 1872 January 25 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Addresses: Masonic Lodge: Galveston, Texas, 1868 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Addresses: Masonic Lodge: Houston, Texas, undated (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Addresses: Masonic Lodge: Independence, Texas, 1868 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Addresses: Masonic Lodge: Mississippi, 1848-1852 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Addresses: Mexia Educational Convention and University of Mississippi, 1851-1883 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Addresses: Mississippi, 1851-1859 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Addresses: Outlines: (1 of 2), undated (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Addresses: Outlines: (2 of 2), undated (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - Addresses: “Plan for a State University”, 1875 February 15 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Addresses: Robert E. Lee Memorial, 1870 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Addresses: “Should the Higher Education of Youth be Committed to the State?”: (1 of 2), undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Addresses: “Should the Higher Education of Youth be Committed to the State?”: (2 of 2), undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Addresses: Washington County: History, 1876 July 4 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Addresses: General, 1833-1835 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Addresses: General, 1843 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Addresses: General, 1847-1848 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Addresses: General, 1850 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Addresses: General, 1851-1852 June (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Addresses: General, 1852 July-1857 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Addresses: General, 1861-1874 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Addresses: General: (1 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Addresses: General: (2 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Addresses: General: (3 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Addresses: General: (4 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Addresses: General: (5 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Addresses: General: (6 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Addresses: General: (7 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Addresses: General: (8 of 8), undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Book: Newspaper Articles: New York Mirror, 1833 (Box 47 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials: Centennial Certificate, 1876 July 4 (Box 47 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: Religious Herald, 1884 May 1 (Box 47 OVZ, Folder 3)
- Photographic Materials, 1852-1912, undated; 7
  This series contains photographs, visiting cards, and prints pertaining to William Carey Crane and his immediate family.
  - Photos: Visiting Cards: William Carey Crane and Rev. Z. Taylor, 1872- 1882, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Photos: Crane Family, 1852-1890, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Photos: Crane Family, 1902 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Photos: Crane Family, 1912 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Photos: General, 1882-1884, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Ambrotype: Stereoscope, 1864 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Prints: William Carey Crane and Baylor University, 1874-1907, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)